Guide to the Perspectives on Cormac McCarthy Collection
The Wittliff Collections
Perspectives on Cormac McCarthy Collection
1991-1993
The Wittliff Collections
Arnold, Edwin "Chip"; Luce, Dianne
SWWC.039
1 Linear Feet
2 boxes
The Perspectives on Cormac McCarthy Collection includes drafts and proofs of essays by several authors on novelist Cormac McCarthy. The essays were edited by Edwin "Chip" Arnold and Dianne Luce, and appeared in Perspectives on Cormac McCarthy, the book version of the Southern Quarterly, published by the University Press of Mississippi, September 1993.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Edwin "Chip" Arnold, 1996
Organizational History
The Southern Quarterly, a journal of the arts in the South, is published by the University of Southern Mississippi, in Hattiesburg, Mississippi.
Scope and Contents
This collection is comprised of drafts and proofs of essays by various authors focusing on novelist Cormac McCarthy. The essays were edited by Edwin "Chip" Arnold and Dianne Luce, and appeared in Perspectives on Cormac McCarthy, the book version of the Southern Quarterly, published by the University Press of Mississippi, September 1993.
The collection has been arranged into the two series: Drafts, Proofs, and Correspondence. Dates range from 1991 to 1993.
Authors, American; American literature -- History and criticism; McCarthy, Cormac, 1933-; Arnold, Edwin "Chip"; Luce, Dianne
- Drafts, circa 1991
  Series Description
  The Drafts series includes photocopies of typewritten, hand annotated drafts, accompanied in many cases by brief correspondence regarding the status of the draft. Some folders include several drafts. Arranged alphabetically by last name of the author.
  - Preface, circa 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Arnold, Edwin "Chip", circa 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Cheuse, Alan, circa 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Daugherty, Leo, circa 1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Grammer, John, circa 1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Luce, Dianne, circa 1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Morrison, Gail Moore, circa 1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ragan, David Paul, circa 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sepich, John Emil, circa 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Shaviro, Steven, circa 1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Wallace, Garry, circa 1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Young, Thomas D., Jr., circa 1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Proofs, circa 1993
  Proofs are arranged in alphabetical order by the last name of the author, followed by one set of proofs for the work as a whole.
  - Preface, circa 1993 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Arnold, Edwin "Chip", circa 1993 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Cheuse, Alan, circa 1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Daugherty, Leo, circa 1993 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Grammer, John, circa 1993 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Luce, Dianne, circa 1993 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Morrison, Gail Moore, circa 1993 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Ragan, David Paul, circa 1993 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Sepich, John Emil, circa 1993 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Shaviro, Steven, circa 1993 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Wallace, Garry, circa 1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Young, Thomas D., Jr., circa 1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Annotated Laser Proofs of entire work, circa 1993 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
- Correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)